A Guide to the Sara Josepha Hale Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7639-d
Sara Josepha Hale Collection 1889-1931
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7639-d
9 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Transfer 1995 November 28
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Mary E. Tyler to Judge W. E. Ambler, 1889 Feb 12; ALS, 2 p.
    [Revealing the name of an early playmate and a classmate of Mr. Roulstone, thanking him for the offer of a lamb picture but declining as she has been presented with many others, and politely refusing to send a photograph of herself.
  - Carroll A. Wilson to Richard W. Hale, Boston, Massachusetts, 1930 Dec 23; TL (carbon), 3 p.
    [Discussing the authorship of [
    Mary Had a Little Lamb
    ], including the claim of Mary Sawyer[ Mary E. Tyler?] that the poem was written by Sarah Josepha Hale for her twenty five years previously. He further discusses evidence attempting to identify the author of the poem, including a statement by Hale that she wrote the poem and that she wrote it as a allegory "to teach the loving-kindness that should find happiness in making helpless creatures happy." He states certain differences in the two versions of the poem, one published in the 1830 September-October issue of
    Juvenile Miscellany
    , with the initials 'S. J. H.' following the verse which was entitled 'Mary's Lamb' and the other the book, [
    ]. He also inquires about "the Old South wool-selling" and mentions Mr. Ford and Mr. Roulstone's theory.]
  - Richard W. Hale, Hale and Dorr, Boston, Massachusetts, to Carroll A. Wilson, New York, New York, 1930 Dec 24; TLS, 2 p.
    [Discussing further the authorship of
    , and mentioning "the Old South wool selling," Mrs. Emmet [Ruth E.]Finley and her forthcoming biography of Hale, and Sarah Hunter, descendant of Hale.]
  - Ruth E. Finley, Hempstead, Long Island, New York, to Carroll A. Wilson, New York, New York, 1931 Jan 4; TLS, 1 p.
    [Asking him to talk about his attitude concerning the authorship of '
    Mary's Little Lamb
    , ' mentioning the Ford controversy and the 1830 September-October issue of
    . ]
  - Carroll A. Wilson to Ruth E. Finley, Hempstead, Long Island, New York, 1931 Jan 6; TL (carbon), 1 p.
    [Offering to send the needed photographic illustration [from
    ] and asking to borrow the clipping from the
    Boston Transcript
    which appeared after "the Old South Church Wool-Selling incident."]
  - Richard W. Hale, Hale and Dorr, Boston, Massachusetts, to Carroll A. Wilson, New York, New York, 1931 Jan 7; TLS, 1 p.
    [Commenting on 'the old South wool-selling' and the corresponding article in the
  - Ruth E. Finley, Hempstead, Long Island, New York, to Carroll A. Wilson, New York, New York, 1931 Jan 13; TLS, 1 p.
    [Thanking him for the promise of the photograph of the first printing of "
    " and enclosing a copy of the article from the
  - Carroll A. Wilson to Ruth E. Finley, Hempstead, Long Island, New York, 1931 Jan 15; TL (carbon), 2 p.
    [Thanking her for the copy of the article and enclosing a photograph of the poem as well as one of the original wrapper number of the issue of the [
    ].]
  - Ruth E. Finley, Hempstead, Long Island, New York, to Carroll A. Wilson, New York, New York, 1931 Jan 20; TLS, 1 p.
    [Expressing her gratitude for the two photographs from the issue of the
    and discussing the chapter on "
    Mary's Lamb
    . " She comments on writing about the character and achievements of Sarah Josepha Hale and "the Raulston -Sawyer -Hale -Ford affair."]